<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NLP | RATUL GHOSH</title>
    <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/nlp/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/nlp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>NLP</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ratulghosh.github.io/images/icon_hua80dc707618ccdeb04ec20a728b72544_14783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>NLP</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/nlp/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loan Document Verification</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and Developed Events driven pipeline for Document Classification, Signature Detection &amp;amp; Verification with State of the art Named Entity Recognition. All documents (Payslips, Self-Certifications, ID cards) were scanned and extracted data were feed into a CRM. for sub-Saharan Africa. This solution was developed for sub-Saharan Africa where financial inclusion is still very limited. The solution reduced the previous verification time from 2 weeks per client (manual) to around 30 minutes by automating the entire process using Machine Learning. Due to lack of proper network infrastructure in most of sub-Saharan Africa, we deployed machine learning models to run on edge devices for document recognition and extraction of relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAX</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/max/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/max/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAX is an artificial intelligent Conversation UX that understands natural language through voice and text. It engages in a conversation with a user, understands his/her intent, and helps user performing actions by connecting to relevant applications through APIs. It is a zero coding system and enables businesses to add new use cases(conversation)) on their own. The product won the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasscom.in/knowledge-center/publications/top-50-ai-game-changers-compendium-best-ai-solutions-use-cases&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NASSCOM Top 50 AI Game Changers award.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sceptre</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and Developed Events driven pipeline for Document Classification, Signature Detection &amp;amp; Verification with State of the art Named Entity Recognition. All documents (Payslips, Self-Certifications , ID cards) were scanned and extracted data were feed into a CRM. for sub-Saharan Africa. This solution was developed for sub-Saharan Africa where financial inclusion is still very limited. The solution reduced the previous verification time from 2 weeks per client (manual) to around 30 minuted by automating
the entire process using Machine Learning. Due to lack of proper network infrastructure in most of sub-Saharan Africa, we deployed machine learning models to run on edge devices for document recognition and extraction of relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEMSE</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/semse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/semse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Semse is a search tool that extracts business knowledge trapped inside thousands of documents by mitigating users&amp;rsquo; struggle of finding information that they are looking for. Semse uses all documents in as-is, where-is basis. It automatically learns entire knowledge from all the documents using state of the art deep learning techniques. It is a language-independent search engine that lets users ask questions in any language. It reduces the manual efforts of preparing training data and organizing questions from users. It also uses iterative learning and continuously evolves based on usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeriTrade</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and Developed Events driven pipeline for Document Classification, Signature Detection &amp;amp; Verification with State of the art Named Entity Recognition. All documents (Payslips, Self-Certifications , ID cards) were scanned and extracted data were feed into a CRM. for sub-Saharan Africa. This solution was developed for sub-Saharan Africa where financial inclusion is still very limited. The solution reduced the previous verification time from 2 weeks per client (manual) to around 30 minuted by automating
the entire process using Machine Learning. Due to lack of proper network infrastructure in most of sub-Saharan Africa, we deployed machine learning models to run on edge devices for document recognition and extraction of relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
