<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RATUL GHOSH</title>
    <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ratulghosh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>RATUL GHOSH</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ratulghosh.github.io/images/icon_hua80dc707618ccdeb04ec20a728b72544_14783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>RATUL GHOSH</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content-Based Image Retrieval and Clustering for Collaborative Slam</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/tcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/tcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Bias in Posters</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/movie-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/movie-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InstaKYC</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/instakyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/instakyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InstaKYC is an awarding winning deep learning based platform designed to transform &amp;amp; automate KYC processes and needs for both clients and banks. It covers all key stages of KYC; from onboarding, performing KYC remediation to reviews within seconds. The platform is deployed in France, Romania &amp;amp; Serbia. Brought in a savings of 100 FTE &amp;amp; reduced the remediation time from 20 minutes per client (manual) to 40 seconds (automated) by automating the entire process using Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loan Document Verification</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and Developed Events driven pipeline for Document Classification, Signature Detection &amp;amp; Verification with State of the art Named Entity Recognition. All documents (Payslips, Self-Certifications, ID cards) were scanned and extracted data were feed into a CRM. for sub-Saharan Africa. This solution was developed for sub-Saharan Africa where financial inclusion is still very limited. The solution reduced the previous verification time from 2 weeks per client (manual) to around 30 minutes by automating the entire process using Machine Learning. Due to lack of proper network infrastructure in most of sub-Saharan Africa, we deployed machine learning models to run on edge devices for document recognition and extraction of relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAX</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/max/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/max/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MAX is an artificial intelligent Conversation UX that understands natural language through voice and text. It engages in a conversation with a user, understands his/her intent, and helps user performing actions by connecting to relevant applications through APIs. It is a zero coding system and enables businesses to add new use cases(conversation)) on their own. The product won the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nasscom.in/knowledge-center/publications/top-50-ai-game-changers-compendium-best-ai-solutions-use-cases&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NASSCOM Top 50 AI Game Changers award.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Stream</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/moviestream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/moviestream/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote class=&#34;embedly-card&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/i2h-ovxYuGs?t=40&#34;&gt;demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;null&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/platform.js&#34; charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the code 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RatulGhosh/movie-stream&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sceptre</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sceptre is a platform built for conducting AI/ML related experiments. On-fly OCR functionality with the option to choose Tesseract (Open source) Engine, ABBYY Engine, or Azure OCR. Ability to create multiple projects with different versions and tag documents on the platform itself for recognition and extraction purpose. The platform lets users choose different algorithms for document extraction and define business-specific heuristics. The platform can also run multiple consistency checks and rules specified by the business. Finally, the platform will list down the documents where some validation failed and requires additional review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security &amp; Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/securitynode/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/securitynode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;IoT based general purpose Security and Surveillance system for home, office, traffic etc. The application continuously records videos and if there is any motion a signal is sent to the Node Mcu which in turn triggers a buzzer. There is an extended application of integrating with the Dropbox API so that the system can automatically upload security photos to our personal Dropbox account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;embedly-card&#34;&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/RatulGhosh/Security-and-Surveillance/master/images/giphy.gif&#34;&gt;null&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;null&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/platform.js&#34; charset=&#34;UTF-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the code 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/RatulGhosh/Security-and-Surveillance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEMSE</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/semse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/semse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Semse is a search tool that extracts business knowledge trapped inside thousands of documents by mitigating users&amp;rsquo; struggle of finding information that they are looking for. Semse uses all documents in as-is, where-is basis. It automatically learns entire knowledge from all the documents using state of the art deep learning techniques. It is a language-independent search engine that lets users ask questions in any language. It reduces the manual efforts of preparing training data and organizing questions from users. It also uses iterative learning and continuously evolves based on usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMART GRID</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/smart-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/smart-grid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The objective of this project is to conserve electricity using IoT-based Smart Grid incorporating different sensors at the power station and houses. Manually determining the root cause of failures is often tedious for a complex system operating in large-scale distributed heterogeneous environments. The model is used to maximize the utility of the consumer, subject to a minimum daily energy consumption level, maximum and minimum hourly load levels, and ramping limits on such load levels. Monitoring the real-time data of the power consumption by the appliances connected to a network and if less than a certain value the re-routing of power to some other place which is in need takes place. A smart meter which delivers the real-time data consumption by the consumers. Fault in one grid leads to the re-routing of power through the nearest grid. A simple bidirectional communication between the power supplier and the consumer enables the implementation of the proposed model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ece.iiita.ac.in/project.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeriTrade</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Veritrade is a solution to automate trade finance verification. The solution uses state of the art deep learning to first identify the type of documents from 23 different categories like Bill of Lading, Letter of Credit, Invoice, etc. Once a document is classified the solution extracts critical information like issue date, type of commodity, billing address, etc from each of those 23 documents using a hybrid approach comprising of both machine learning and heuristics. The information extraction approach is robust enough to handle different variations across the same documents.
The solution then runs around 4000 consistency checks and rules specified by UCP and ISBP. The rules and consistency checks can be intra and inter documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of Veritrade:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massive efficiency gains of ~80%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drastically reduces the operational risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brings objectivity to the UCP/ISBP rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible to quickly adapt to any UCP/ISBP rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates training cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applications of Deep Learning in Medical Imaging</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/second/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/second/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please cite using following bibtex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@incollection{maitra2019applications,
  title={Applications of Deep Learning in Medical Imaging},
  author={Maitra, Sanjit and Ghosh, Ratul and Ghosh, Kuntal},
  booktitle={Handbook of Deep Learning Applications},
  pages={111--127},
  year={2019},
  publisher={Springer, Cham}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep representation learning characterized by inter-class separation for image clustering</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please cite using following bibtex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@INPROCEEDINGS{8658417,
  author={D. {Das} and R. {Ghosh} and B. {Bhowmick}},
  booktitle={2019 IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)}, 
  title={Deep Representation Learning Characterized by Inter-Class Separation for Image Clustering}, 
  year={2019},
  volume={},
  number={},
  pages={628-637},}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic detection and classification of diabetic retinopathy stages using CNN</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/third/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/publication/third/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please cite using following bibtex:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@inproceedings{ghosh2017automatic,
  title={Automatic detection and classification of diabetic retinopathy stages using CNN},
  author={Ghosh, Ratul and Ghosh, Kuntal and Maitra, Sanjit},
  booktitle={2017 4th International Conference on Signal Processing and Integrated Networks (SPIN)},
  pages={550--554},
  year={2017},
  organization={IEEE}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/dr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/dr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aparoksha</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/feast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/feast/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Segmentation using CNN</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/segmentation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Features Classification from RISAT-1 Polarized Image using CNN</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/landfeature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/landfeature/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mutation Level Prediction</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/mutation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/mutation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
