<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer Vision | RATUL GHOSH</title>
    <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/computer-vision/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/computer-vision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Computer Vision</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ratulghosh.github.io/images/icon_hua80dc707618ccdeb04ec20a728b72544_14783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/tag/computer-vision/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content-Based Image Retrieval and Clustering for Collaborative Slam</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/tcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/tcs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Bias in Posters</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/movie-gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/movie-gender/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InstaKYC</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/instakyc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/instakyc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;InstaKYC is an awarding winning deep learning based platform designed to transform &amp;amp; automate KYC processes and needs for both clients and banks. It covers all key stages of KYC; from onboarding, performing KYC remediation to reviews within seconds. The platform is deployed in France, Romania &amp;amp; Serbia. Brought in a savings of 100 FTE &amp;amp; reduced the remediation time from 20 minutes per client (manual) to 40 seconds (automated) by automating the entire process using Machine Learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loan Document Verification</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/ldv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Designed and Developed Events driven pipeline for Document Classification, Signature Detection &amp;amp; Verification with State of the art Named Entity Recognition. All documents (Payslips, Self-Certifications, ID cards) were scanned and extracted data were feed into a CRM. for sub-Saharan Africa. This solution was developed for sub-Saharan Africa where financial inclusion is still very limited. The solution reduced the previous verification time from 2 weeks per client (manual) to around 30 minutes by automating the entire process using Machine Learning. Due to lack of proper network infrastructure in most of sub-Saharan Africa, we deployed machine learning models to run on edge devices for document recognition and extraction of relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sceptre</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/sceptre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sceptre is a platform built for conducting AI/ML related experiments. On-fly OCR functionality with the option to choose Tesseract (Open source) Engine, ABBYY Engine, or Azure OCR. Ability to create multiple projects with different versions and tag documents on the platform itself for recognition and extraction purpose. The platform lets users choose different algorithms for document extraction and define business-specific heuristics. The platform can also run multiple consistency checks and rules specified by the business. Finally, the platform will list down the documents where some validation failed and requires additional review.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VeriTrade</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/veritrade/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Veritrade is a solution to automate trade finance verification. The solution uses state of the art deep learning to first identify the type of documents from 23 different categories like Bill of Lading, Letter of Credit, Invoice, etc. Once a document is classified the solution extracts critical information like issue date, type of commodity, billing address, etc from each of those 23 documents using a hybrid approach comprising of both machine learning and heuristics. The information extraction approach is robust enough to handle different variations across the same documents.
The solution then runs around 4000 consistency checks and rules specified by UCP and ISBP. The rules and consistency checks can be intra and inter documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages of Veritrade:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massive efficiency gains of ~80%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drastically reduces the operational risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brings objectivity to the UCP/ISBP rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible to quickly adapt to any UCP/ISBP rules&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates training cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/dr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/dr/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Segmentation using CNN</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/segmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/segmentation/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Land Features Classification from RISAT-1 Polarized Image using CNN</title>
      <link>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/landfeature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ratulghosh.github.io/project/landfeature/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
